# Carroll Vance

Email: cs.vance AT icloud.com Github: https://github.com/csvance

## **Profile**

I am currently an undergraduate student studying Computer Science at the University of Houston. I have professional experience working with embedded systems for a variety of applications including robotics/automation, networking, and storage. I also have a passion for machine learning/data science and am currently involved with a research group on campus doing time series prediction for pollution data in an HPC environment.

### Skills

Developed applications for embedded micro controllers and microprocessors such as PIC, ARM Cortex M0, M3, M4, A7, A57 and more. Experience with embedded Linux ranging from board bringup to custom distribution creation with Yocto Project. Proficient in both C and Python. Created ROS nodes for motor control/odometry, object detection, and IMU data acquisition. Trained, optimized, and deployed convolutional neural networks for object detection and classification on an embedded system. Experience training various CNN, LSTM, Deep-Q, and Random Forest machine learning models.

## Education

**UNIVERSITY OF HOUSTON – 2018-CURRENT** 

Expected Graduation: Fall 2020 with B.S. in Computer Science & Minor in Mathematics

HOUSTON COMMUNITY COLLEGE – 2016-2018
Studied Computer Science

**CUMULATIVE GPA – 4.0** 

# Experience

SOFTWARE ENGINEER, WILDCAT DEVELOPMENT; SPRING, TEXAS – 2009-2016

Designed and implemented embedded software for companies such as Baker Hughes, Hewlett Packard Enterprise, and National Oilwell Varco

SYSTEMS VALIDATION TESTER, WAILUA TECHNOLOGY; HOUSTON, TEXAS – 2008-2009

Executed test plan for flash memory technology created by Spansion and Virident Systems

### Extracurricular

CULLEN COLLEGE OF ENGINEERING IEEE – MAKERSPACE OFFICER, 2018-CURRENT DATA ANALYTICS IN STUDENT HANDS - MEMBER, 2018-CURRENT